macinstruct.com 2003-02-10

# MacInstruct : : Privacy Policy

MacInstruct respects the privacy of the personal information you give us, such as your name, street address, telephone number and e-mail address, and other personal information you may provide. The following policy is intended to explain how we treat this information. This policy may change, so please check back from time to time. 

**Traffic data**  
Each time a visitor comes to a MacInstruct web site, our servers collect some basic technical information, including, for example, the visitor's domain name (i.e., the ISP from which the user is logged on). We use software to keep track of traffic to our sites and derive such information as the location from which the traffic originates and which particular pages within MacInstruct are being viewed and for how long. After we analyze this information, we discard it. We may aggregate information about visitors and traffic and may share the results with advertisers; generally, we will not disclose your individual identity or personally identifiable data that you supply us without your permission. It will only be used to contact you in case you win a contest. 

**Information Security and Quality**  
We intend to protect the quality and integrity of your personally identifiable information. We have implemented appropriate technical and managerial procedures to maintain information that is accurate, current, and complete. We will make a sincere effort to respond to your requests to correct personal information inaccuracies in a timely manner. 

**Newsletters and Other E-mail Features**  
If you sign up to receive an e-mail newsletter from MacInstruct, such newsletters will be sent on a daily or weekly basis. You may also receive infrequent other announcements from MacInstruct. We will use your e-mail address for the distribution of these newsletters and announcements. Users can choose to unsubscribe from MacInstruct newsletters at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions found in each e-mail. 

**Use of Cookies**  
A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. MacInstruct does not generally make use of cookies, although it is possible that they may be used in a limited way to assist in the delivery of advertisements, to identify how many unique visitors there are to the MacInstruct site and to track usage.

Other companies that place advertising on our site also have the ability to assign their cookies to you in a process that MacInstruct does not control. 

In the event that MacInstruct starts to use Cookies more widely, they will never be used to track websites you visit other than MacInstruct. Some parties use cookies to view sites you visit other than their own, to assess your "viewing habits." MacInstruct will not subscribe to this practice. 

**Contests**  
MacInstruct may sponsor sweepstakes, contests or other events from time to time which require the collection, processing and storage of certain contact and demographic information (e.g., place of residence) for use as part of the contest. Sometimes these contests may be jointly-sponsored with companies. In that case the user's contact and other information will be shared with the other company only if it is expressly stated in the rules of the contest. 

However, such contests will include the option to receive e-mail from our partners regarding their products or services. If you sign up for such an e-mail list, we will release your e-mail address to our partner for the purpose of such mailings, and only for that purpose. We will not release any of your other personal information to that partner. If you do not sign up for such an e-mail list, our partners will receive no information on you - including your e-mail address - even if you enter the associated contest or promotion. 

**Surveys**  
MacInstruct may conduct voluntary surveys of visitors to the site to collect certain demographic information about visitors to its site. This information may be compiled and shared in the aggregate with advertisers and other third parties, but no personal details will be traceable or associated with specific readers. 

**Children's Privacy**  
Protecting the privacy of young children is important to us. For that reason, MacInstruct will not collect or maintain information at its web site from those actually known to be under 13, and no part of MacInstruct is intentionally structured to attract anyone under 13\. The sole exception to this is our mailing lists. If a child under 13 signs up for our newsletter or any of our mailing lists, they will remain a member unless we are asked to remove them by their parent or legal guardian. All such requests should be directed to [matt@macinstruct.com](mailto:matt@macinstruct.com).

**Other Disclosure of Personal Information**  
MacInstruct will not otherwise disclose or make use of personal information without consent of the user except (i) as described in this privacy policy, or (ii) as required by law, court order or as requested by other government or law enforcement authority. This policy does not protect information you post to any on-line bulletin board, chat room, newsgroup or other public forum within the MacInstruct site. 

**Other Sites**  
MacInstruct may contain links to sites on the Internet operated by others. MacInstruct cannot control and is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other web sites. 

**Unsubscribe and Data Removal Policies**  
If you would like to unsubscribe from a MacInstruct newsletter, please follow the instructions at the bottom of the newsletter itself or email your request to [matt@macinstruct.com](mailto:matt@macinstruct.com)

**Who Can I Ask if I Have Any Additional Questions?**  
If you have any further questions or concerns about MacInstruct's privacy policies and use of personal information, please send them to [matt@macinstruct.com](mailto:matt@macinstruct.com).
